本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：marvin      校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
斯凯勒  我实在是
Skyler, I'm so...
玛丽  天啊  玛丽  怎样了
Marie. Oh, Christ, Marie. How...
天啊
Oh, God.
感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
她漂亮吗
Is she beautiful?
我现在堵在40号公路上
I'm staring at brake lights on the 40.
前方好像出了什么事故
Some accident up ahead.
总算盼到这一天了  是吧
Christ. Today of all days, huh?
先让她休息吧  我尽快赶过去
Let her rest. I'll be there as soon as I can.
玛丽  谢谢你
Marie, thank you.
打扰一下  斯凯勒·怀特哪个房间
Excuse me. Skyler White?
307号房
307.
谢谢
Thank you.
斯凯勒  实在抱歉  我
Skyler, I'm so sorry. I'm just...
你还好吗
Are you okay?
来见见你女儿吧
Meet your daughter.
你好啊  小丫头
Hi, there, girl.
你好啊  霍莉
Hi, there, Holly.
恭喜你了  沃特
Congratulations, Walt.
泰德  抱歉  我没注意到你在这儿
Ted. I'm sorry, I didn't see you here.
泰德开车送我来的  太感谢了
Ted drove me here. Thank God.
我是说  我俩这次喜得千金
I mean, this little bundle of joy of ours
还真多亏了泰德
Was practically on rails.
半路上的时候我差点觉得
Halfway here I thought he was gonna have
他要停车亲自帮我接生了
To pull over and deliver her himself.
还好没到那地步
Then, I'm glad it didn't come to that.
谢谢你  泰德
Yeah, thanks Ted.
不用客气
No problem at all.
那我先走吧  让你们俩
Well, let me get out of your way here so you two can,
你们三位 可以独处一会吧
You three, can be alone, okay?
听着  放松点  斯凯勒
Listen, take it easy, Sky.
我真是  不知道该怎么谢你了
I really... I can't begin to thank you...
别这么想  这是我的荣幸
Don't think anything of it. It's my pleasure.
再次恭喜你们了
Congratulations again.
-谢谢你  -她很漂亮
- Thank you. - She's beautiful.
-以后再聊吧  -保重
- I'll talk to you soon. - Okay, Take care.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-都还好吧  -都还好
- Is everything okay?  - Everything's okay.
我只是希望你当时能陪着我
I just wish you'd been here.
其他人呢
Where's everyone else?
楼下
Downstairs.
汉克和玛丽带小沃特去吃晚饭了
Hank and Marie took Junior for dinner.
他甚至自告奋勇
He has been such a trooper.
帮忙换了第一块尿布
He even changed his first diaper.
真的吗
Did he?
亲爱的  我能为你做点什么吗
Honey, is there anything that I can do for you?
任何事都可以
Anything at all?
当然有
Actually, yes.
早上我把旅行包忘家里了
I left my overnight bag at home this morning.
你应该知道的  破腹产  还记得吗
I think you get it in your head, "C-section." You know?
我很高兴一切都很顺利
But I'm just so glad the way it all worked out.
事情来的自然而然
Doing it natural instead.
再没有比这更好的了
It just couldn't have gone any better.
好的
Good.
那我  去拿你的东西吧
Let me... go get your things.
顺便也整点东西来  好吗
And I'll... get my stuff, too, okay?
我在这过夜
I'll spend the night.
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第十二集
爸爸
Dad.
我刚刚在洗澡
I was in the shower.
我睡过头了
I overslept.
我要迟到了  但是我会去的
I'm running late, but I'll be there.
宝贝  我得走了
Baby, I gotta go.
有人闯进来了
Somebody broke in.
不  不  不  不
Oh, no no no no...
该死
Damn.
天啊
Oh, God.
我的天
Oh, Christ.
这周真是糟糕
This week was tough.
最糟糕的了
Toughest yet.
知道为什么吗
You know why?
我知道会有这一天
I knew this day was coming.
-我的生日  -你的重生之日
- My birthday. - Your re-birthday?
日子越近  情况就越糟
Yeah, and as it got closer, it got worse.
我很害怕我做不到
I was scared shitless I wouldn't make it.
我确实觉得自己不行
I really didn't think I would.
连续请了三天病假
Called in sick three days in a row.
我知道我老板被惹毛了
I know my boss was pissed.
我知道自己不在乎
I guess I don't really care.
我只是不想见任何人
I just didn't want to see anybody.
你们大家知道是怎么回事吧
You guys know how that is.
所需要的一切就是一位朋友
All it'd take is one friend
然后我就可以继续活蹦乱跳了
And I'd be out ripping and running again.
但是我做到了  我真的做到了
But I made it. I really made it.
我一年没碰了  一直坚持到这一天
I got one year clean to the day.
你好像很累  你的眼睛有点发红
You look tired. Your eyes are kind of red.
睡饱了吗
You getting enough sleep?
实际上没有
Actually, no.
我一直在搞一个非常复杂的纹身
I'm working on this really complex new tat.
那家伙想在他背上纹满
A guy wants his whole back done up.
要有斧头  大量的火焰
Him on his chopper, flames all around.
我一直给他看设计稿
I keep showing him the design
他一直要求这改那改
And he keeps asking for changes, like,
"多弄点肌肉  多弄点火焰"
"Give me more muscles. Give me more flames."
我就说  "第一  这不是西斯廷教堂
And I'm like, "A, this ain't the Sistine Chapel.
"第二  对付你身上的痘痘就已经够麻烦了"
"And B, I have enough trouble working around your zits."
我真的不愿意你在那种地方工作
I really wish you wouldn't work at that place.
-你要少接触那些  -知道了  我会的
- You need to avoid those type of... - I know... and I do.
大多是大学生和科特兰空军基地的飞行员
It's mostly college kids and airmen from Kirtland.
基本都是三五成群的来
It's actually really corporate.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的工作怎么样了
So, how's your job?
老样子  老样子
Oh, you know. Same old, same old.
休假日还得做后备训练
Doing backup training on my days off.
天  他们现在谁都敢招
God, they're hiring anybody now.
没经验的都行  太可怕了
No experience at all. It's scary.
你最近在谈恋爱吗
You seeing anyone?
隔壁那男的怎么回事
What about that guy next door?
什么意思
What do you mean?
他似乎很期待
Well, he seemed to have some expectation
你介绍我认识他
Of you introducing me to him.
他知道你是房东
He knows you own the place.
爸  他是我们的房客
Dad, he's our tenant.
仅此而已
End of story.
我为什么要跟房客扯上关系
Why would I get involved with a tenant?
她可真美啊
Isn't she beautiful?
我在想她是最最漂亮的小宝宝了
I just think she's the most beautiful baby ever.
可不是嘛
And why not?
将来一定是个名门千金
Good stock.
我去接
I'll get it.
喂  喂
Hello, hello...
挂了
Nobody's there.
抢到了
Beat ya!
-喂  -老兄
- Hello. - Hey, man.
卡门  你好
Oh, hi, Carmen.
是卡门
Just Carmen.
-拜托  快点  -你听说了啊
- Come on. Hurry up. - So you heard?
是好消息啊  她真的很漂亮
Good news. She's just so beautiful.
名叫霍莉
Well, Holly.
她重七磅三盎司
7 pounds, 3 ounces.
一切都好
Everybody is doing just fine.
你个二百五  打这个号码做什么
You junkie imbecile. What are you calling this number for?
我告诉你  老兄
I am trying to tell you, man.
昨晚有人闯进我家里了
Last night, somebody broke in my place, yo.
-我被抢了  -什么
- I got robbed. - What?
有人  偷走了我们所有的
Somebody, they got all of our...
所有的东西
Our stuff.
一点不剩
All of it.
懂了没  怀特先生
You get me, Mr. White?
那些冰毒  太离奇了
The blue stuff. It's, like, uncanny.
他们知道具体位置
They knew exactly where to look!
你吱一声啊  老兄
I mean, say something, man!
吼几句啊  拜托  怀特先生
Yell at me or something! Come on!  Mr.White.
汉克  快点  大伙都快饿死了
Hank, come on!  People are starving to death out here!
好啦好啦  啤酒可不能少啊
All right, all right. Had to get a beer.
好了  开始吧
All right, guys. Here we go.
有不辣  微辣和超辣的
We got mild, medium and muy caliente.
我要吃胸部的肉
I got dibs on the breast.
洛博罗炸鸡馆
Los Pollos Hermanos?
是啊  你尝尝
Yeah, seriously. You gotta try it.
这家店抢了肯德基不少生意
This joint gives KFC a run for their money.
小宝宝饿了哦
That baby's hungry.
把宝宝给我
Give me that baby.
来  小甜心
Aw, sweetie, here.
拜托  斯凯勒  不要再在餐桌旁吧  吃东西在呢
Come on. Jeez, Sky. Not at the table. We're eating.
汉克  不就是乳房吗
Hank, it's only a breast.
-是我嫂子的乳房  -你真封建啊你
- It's my sister-in-law's breast. - You are so provincial.
你还记得那天
Remember the day
我们谈论关于孩子防护的问题吗
When you were talking to me about child-proofing?
你怎么看   用围栏还是棚子
What are you thinking?  A fence or a cover?
我还是觉得用警报系统比较好
Actually, I was thinking more of an alarm system.
现在有套新的系统
They've got these new systems out there,
声纳系统可以做到
"sonar systems" that would...
只要有东西进入  警报就会响起
Anything falls into it, it sets the alarm off.
听起来很贵吧
That sounds expensive.
嗯  也是  不过  为了宝宝
Well, yeah, but... for the baby, I mean...
为什么不
Why don't...
为什么不让我和玛丽买台送你们呢
Why don't you let Marie and I get that for you guys?
对啊
Absolutely.
不用  你的好意心领了
No, no, thank you
不用了  我马上就上班了
No, please. I'll be back at work soon.
我们会想办法的
We'll take care of it.
马上就上班
Back at work soon?
因为你要做手术嘛  所以我想
Since you're scheduled for surgery, I just thought
多赚点钱是好事
It might be a good idea to have some money coming in.
斯凯勒  我们得为宝宝多考虑一下
Skyler, we need to think about what's best for the baby.
我觉得她妈妈应该
And I think having her mother around
前几年都呆在宝宝身边
For at least the first few years...
至于钱  我们会想办法  我保证
Money-wise, we'll manage. I promise you that.
怎么
What?
你们在车库里印钞票
You guys got a printing press in the garage churning out 50s?
我希望如此
I wish.
妈妈还说让我找个工作
Mom's even talking about me getting a job.
对  人人参与
That's right. Everybody pitches in.
为什么不吃一次中国菜
Why don't we ever get Chinese?
我来
I'll get her.
乖宝宝
Good girl.
真是乖宝宝
That's a good girl.
我的小宝贝
My little girl, huh?
想看看什么吗
Do you want to see something?
来
Come here.
我知道我知道
Oh. I know, I know.
你想看看爸爸给你准备了什么
You want to see what your daddy did for you?
我带你看看
Let me show you.
这儿  过来
Here. Come here.
想看吗
Want to see?
就是这个了
That's right.
爸爸挣得
Daddy did that.
爸爸为你挣得
Daddy did that for you.
这地方看起来没什么变化
This place looks exactly the same.
你为什么不用电脑啥的呢
Why don't you have computers and shit?
现在又不是20世纪
It's the 20th century.
你来这搞什么鬼
What the hell are you doing here?
是你把东西拿跑了
You took the stash!
我听了所有的电话留言  终于搞明白了
I heard all those phone messages and I figured it out.
你搞明白了  恭喜啊  爱因斯坦
You figured it out?  Congratulations, Einstein.
你让我着急了一整天
You left me to freak out all day long,
像是我失职了一样  结果却是你干的好事
Like I dropped the ball!  And you were the one who took it!
闭嘴
Shut up.
你小点声
You lower your voice.
"像是"你失职了
"Like" you dropped the ball?
你什么时候没失过职  杰西
When have you ever not dropped the ball, Jesse?
你脑子里别成天尽想些那什么
Blasted out of your mind on whatever the hell that was.
那什么
What was that?
海洛因
Heroin?
天
Jesus.
我那天休息  我只在休息时吸
I was on my day off. What I do on my day off...
休息  我们可是随时待命  你这瘾君子
Day off?  We were on-call, you junkie.
对于这笔大买卖更是要随时待命
On-call for the biggest deal of our lives.
而且还是我拼了老命
And I just managed to pull it off by
侥幸才争取来的  并非你的帮助
The skin of my teeth, no thanks to you.
你让我错过了我女儿的出生
You made me miss the birth of my daughter.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
多少
How much?
什么多少
How much what?
这笔你赚了多少
How much did you get for the deal?
120万
1.2 million.
对半分
600,000 each.
你拿48万
480,000.
索尔要提百分之二十
Saul's cut is 20%.
那  我的钱呢
So, where's my money?
你开玩笑吧
You are joking, right?
要是我给了你那些钱
If I gave you that money,
你一星期内就得死
you would be dead inside of a week.
听着  我早就不沾海洛因了
Look, I'm off the heroin.
瞧都瞧不上眼  看着就恶心
I didn't even like it anyway. It made me sick.
还有  还有冰毒
And the... And the meth.
对于我来说可有可无
You know, I can take it or leave it.
我已经不吸了  怀特先生
I'm clean, Mr. White.
真的
For real.
证明给我看
Prove it.
用这个取尿样
Pee in that.
-你是幸灾乐祸吗  -快取尿样
- How gay are you?  Seriously. - Pee in it.
现在药店里有卖毒品检测套装
They're selling testing kits at the drug stores.
你要是真不吸了  我就给你钱
If you are clean, I will give you every last dime.
不干
No, huh?
我猜  你以后
Well, I guess, until then,
得依靠
You'll just have to depend on
某个陌生人的怜悯来爽一下了
The kindness of strangers to get high.
包括你的小女友
That and your little junkie girlfriend.
别让她趴着睡  沃特
Not on her tummy, Walt.
我没让她趴着睡
I'm not putting her on her tummy.
我想让她侧着  你扶着她的背吧
I'll put her on her side. Do you want to hold her back?
怕她万一要吐奶
Just in case she decides to do a little spit-up,
我来卷一条毛巾垫在下面
I'll roll up a nice clean towel like this and put it under.
哈马克施莱默公司有这类产品
Hammacher Schlemmer makes a proper one of those.
是低过敏的
It's hypo-allergenic.
我想毛巾就够了
I think a towel will do.
怎么了
What is it?
你儿子
Your son.
真是不可思议  来看看他的杰作
He's just unbelievable. Come see what he did.
跟你说过还没弄好嘛
I told you it's not ready yet.
亲爱的  给他们看看吧
Honey, just show it to them.
天啊  儿子  太棒了
My God, son. That's wonderful.
做的太漂亮了
This is beautiful.
SaveWalterWhite.com  [救助沃尔特怀特.com]
SaveWalterWhite.com.
我呢 准备告诉所有人
Well, I, for one, am telling everybody.
等等
Wait a minute.
你不会是在要钱吧  儿子
You're not asking for money, are you, son?
就是这个意思啊
That's the whole idea.
路易斯帮忙申请了一个贝宝支付账户
Louis helped me set up a PayPal account and everything.
我们不能要钱啊
But we can't ask for money.
我很感动  真的
I appreciate it. I really do.
这主意全是他自己想的
This was all his idea.
他做的可用心了
He worked so hard on it.
就让他帮帮忙吧
Just let him help.
你不能让他放弃吧
You can't ask him to take it down.
那对他可是个打击
It'll crush him.
这可是施舍
It's charity.
你为什么把它说得这么不光彩
Why do you say that like it's some sort of dirty word?
这太荒唐了
This is insane.
我手头有不少现金
I have so much cash on-hand
我还得用浴室的秤来称重
That I actually count it by weighing it on my bathroom scale.
但是  却花不了  也不能告诉家人有这笔钱
And yet, I can't spend it. I can't tell my family about it.
所有人都觉得我濒临破产
All of whom think that I am right on the edge of bankruptcy.
太荒唐了
It's insane.
我猜这就是为什么强盗们都养情妇
Well, I guess that's why gangsters had molls.
什么
What?
就是女同伙
Gun molls.
你没看过《白热杀机》吗
Haven't you ever seen "White Heat"
看过  跟这有什么关系
I've seen "White Heat", but I don't see how that pertains.
或许你更需要一个情妇  而不是一个
Maybe you need a moll more than you need a wife
不能分享你秘密的妻子
Who you can't trust with your secrets.
花不出去的钱还能叫钱吗
What good is money that doesn't spend?
要是一片叶子落进丛林中
If a tree falls in the forest...
你应该懂了吧
You get the point.
沟通是不可行的吗
So communicating is out?
我想想  还有没有别的办法
Well, let's see. What else is there?
总是可以说  "我在铁路下面"
There's always, "Hey, I found a big bag of money
"发现一大袋钱"
"Down by the railroad tracks."
对我管用
Works for me.
默里叔叔
Uncle Murray.
"默里叔叔把我放在膝盖上跳啊跳
"Oh, many is the happy memory
是那么美好的回忆
Of Uncle Murray bouncing me on his knee.
"我们过去都忘记了那老家伙
"We lost track of the old pervert years ago,
"但是你知道吗  他不计前嫌  给了我一百万
"But what do you know?  He kicked it and left me millions."
肯定不会是纯粹的运气或者
It cannot be blind luck or some
假想中的亲戚帮忙
Imaginary relative who saves us.
是我赚来的钱
I earned that money, me.
现在我儿子建了他自己的网站
And now my son created his own website...
"SaveWalterWhite.com"  四处请求匿名捐赠
"SaveWalterWhite.com..." Soliciting anonymous donations.
你知不知道我是什么感受
Do you have any idea how that makes me feel?
看看  还有贝宝
Yeah, look at that. It's got PayPal and everything.
网络乞讨  我就是这么想的
Cyber-begging. That's all that is.
向全世界伸手要钱
Just rattling a little tin cup to the entire world.
也没有更深层次的含义
Yeah, there's no deep-seated issues there.
我已经看到答案了  它正在我眼前晃悠呢
I'm looking at the answer here. It's staring me in the face.
-要我一字一句说出来吗  -不用  我知道
- Do I have to spell it out for you?  - No, I know.
你想让我把钱
You're thinking that I should be funneling my money
全打到我儿子的网站上去  这样绝对不行
Into my son's website, but absolutely not, no.
我可不想让我家人觉得
I am not going to have my family think that some
有一些什么神秘人在资助我们
Mystery benefactor saved us.
不是一些神秘人  就一个
Not some mystery benefactor, singular.
那样的话问题就多起来了
That would raise too many questions.
不管怎样  跟我一起呆着
However... stay with me here...
僵尸  [受他人控制的远程电脑]
Zombies.
我朋友的朋友认识个人
I got a guy who knows this guy
属于"雨人"类型
who knows this Rain Man type.
他在白俄罗斯  跟她妈妈住在地下室里
He lives with his mother in her basement in Belarus.
把他引渡回来时大有好处的
So good luck extraditing his fat Russian ass.
等等
Wait.
他可是个顶级黑客
He's a hacker-cracker extraordinaire.
这人可以操纵世界上任意一台个人电脑
This guy can hijack random desktops
把它们变成僵尸
All around the world,
然后用来捐款
Turn them into zombies that do his bidding.
比如说
For instance,
他可以选择捐20块或者三万块
He can make it so, 20 or 30,000
从全美以及加拿大来的小笔捐款
Little donations come in from all over the U.S. and Canada.
10块  20块  50块积少成多
10, 20, 50 bucks a pop,
做的干净利落  不留痕迹
All paid in-full, nice and neat, untraceable,
来自全世界的热心人士
From the good-hearted people of the world
向沃特先生倾囊相助  帮他与癌症抗争
To Mr. Walter H. White, Cancer Saint.
我想着就振奋人心啊
I'm getting a warm and fuzzy feeling just thinking about it.
他是个混蛋  就这样  总是对我指手画脚
He's an asshole, that's what. Always judging me.
不要太多
Not too much.
我说  他算什么啊
I mean, like... like, who's he, right?
我说  起码是我带他入行的
I mean, first off, I taught him.
他老搞得我像是他的契约仆人一样
He's always acting like I'm his indentured servant.
用棉签
Now the cotton.
用针
Needle?
-我不明白你为什么还需要他  -对
- I don't understand why you need him. - Exactly.
我就这意思
My point exactly.
直直的打进去  这样针就不会乱动
Flat against your skin so it doesn't wiggle around too much.
他欠你多少
How much does he owe you, anyway?
妈的  要是有人欠我500块我也要气死了
Well, hell, I'd be mad, too, if somebody owed me 500 bucks.
不是不是
No,no...
是四十八万
480,000.
什么
What?
万
Thousand.
不要仰着睡  怕万一要吐
Not on your back, baby. In case you throw up.
侧着睡  侧着睡
On your side. Sleep on your side.
她就像在说
She's all like,
"别唠叨了"
"Don't preach to me."
我就说  "宝贝  我没唠叨啊"
And I'm like, "Baby, I'm not preaching to you.
"我在告诉你基本的生存技能  懂吗
"I'm talking about basic survival, you know?
"我在教你认识生命与死亡
"I'm conversing about life and death."
我是说  我们所要做的就是来这儿
I mean, this here, what we've been doing...
见鬼  贝吉知道
Hell, Becky knows.
老爸
Dad?
我睡过了  马上过来
I overslept. I'm on my way.
老爸
Dad?
老爸  等等
Dad, wait.
不是这样的
It's not what it looks like.
老爸  等等  我们谈谈行吗
Dad, just wait. Let me talk to you for one second.
别  别碰他  老爸
Stop it! Don't touch him, Dad!
-混蛋  -老爸  放手
- Son of a bitch. - Dad, let him go!
离我远点  走开
Get away from me, man. Back off.
-后退  -大家冷静一点行吗
- Back off!  - Everybody just calm down!
你搞什么鬼啊你
What's with you, yo?
小心我一棍子砸扁你
'Cause I'll seriously bust you up.
你个恶心的瘾君子
You miserable little smackhead.
-滚出去  -我可是付房租的  贱人
- Get the hell out!  - Hey, I pay my rent, bitch!
我有公民权利
I got civil rights!
杰西  拜托  别  拜托
Jesse, come on. Please, no. Come on.
我自己付房租
I pay my rent.
你回戒毒所去  现在就去
You're going back to rehab. Today. Now.
既然已经这样了  我们就
Look, as it so happens, we were just...
好好谈谈吧
We were just talking about that and...
要是你给我机会的话  我是准备告诉你的
And I was gonna tell you, okay?  If you would just let me.
18个月了
18 months.
你都18个月没沾毒品了  珍妮
You have been clean for 18 months, Jane.
为什么  你为什么这么做
Why? Why do you do it?
我又堕落了  行吗
I backslid, okay?
这又怎样
Like, what?
你觉得我引以为豪吗
What, you think I'm proud of this?
觉得我是故意要这么做吗
Like, I do it on purpose?
还跟这种败类同居鬼混
Shacking up and using with this scumbag, this loser!
你这副德性也好不到哪里去
It takes one to know one!
你不了解他
And you don't know the first thing about him.
我们每天晚上都聊戒毒的事  是他的主意
We talk about rehab every night. It's his idea.
你们讨论戒毒  天  真乖啊你们
You talk about rehab?  Well, gee, isn't that wonderful?
感谢你没有24小时管着我
Thank you for not being judgmental 24 hours a day.
因为那就是我需要的  时刻有人关心
'Cause that's exactly what I need, to be judged all the time!
你知道你需要什么吗  我来告诉你
You know what you need?  I'll tell you exactly.
你干嘛
What are you doing?
-你干嘛啊  -我要报警
- What are you doing?  - I am calling the police.
拜托
Come on!
老爸  别啊
Dad, don't.
我花了十年时间来关爱和理解你
I have tried ten years of love and understanding.
但是最终的结果或许是你在监狱中度过余生
Maybe what it takes is you drying out in a jail cell.
我要报告一起吸毒事件  就在我的房子里
I would like to report drug use in a building that I own.
-不对  正在进行  -爸爸
- No. It's on-going. - Daddy.
这是非法活动  我要跟相关人员报告
It's illegal activity. I'd like to talk to somebody.
-你帮我转接一下  -行  行  我去戒毒中心
- Would you connect me, please?  - Fine, we'll go to rehab.
他去不去我不管
I could care less about him going to rehab.
-我要你去  -行  我明天一大早就去
- I want you in rehab. - Okay. I'll go first thing tomorrow.
明天不行  就今天
Not tomorrow. Today.
我要请假  退订报纸
I have to call into work. I have to stop the newspaper.
上次我去戒毒中心  家里所有的花草都死了
The last time I went to rehab, all my houseplants died
你又不给它们浇水
Because you didn't water them, so...
求您了
Please?
就明天
Tomorrow.
对不起  我搞错了
I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
就明天
Tomorrow.
你来真的
You meant all that?
不晓得
I don't know.
我只是觉得要是我们有足够的钱
I just think if we had enough money,
没人可以逼我们做任何事
nobody could make us do anything.
别去接了
Just let it ring.
我去看看是谁
No, I'm gonna go see who it is.
没事的  霍莉
It's okay, Holly.
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
但是我相信他会乐意写的
But I'm sure he'd be glad to, write some...
他现在在旁边  稍等
Actually, here he is right now. So hold on a second.
-怎么了  -是你的
- What?  - It's one of your...
你的一位学生
One of your old students.
他想让你写一封推荐信
He wants a letter of recommendation.
亲爱的  我觉得宝宝好像饿了
Honey, I think the baby is getting hungry.
-沃特·怀特  请讲 -你好 怀特先生
-This is Walter White. -Hello,Walter White
抱歉  我记忆力有点差
I'm sorry. I'm having a little trouble recalling...
是珍妮
It's Jane.
杰西和珍妮
You know, of Jesse and Jane.
杰西的"小女友"
Jesse's "junkie girlfriend."
当然了  很久以前的事了
Of course. It really has been a long time.
快找个你能讲话的地方
Get somewhere you can talk.
好的  行
Sure. Yes.
我在想办法
I am looking into that as we speak.
你怎么搞到这个号码的
How the hell did you get this number?
杰西给你的吗
Did Jesse give it to you?
杰西只要他的那一份
All Jesse wants is what's coming to him.
仅此而已  再无其他
No more, no less.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
四十八万块
480,000.
他告诉你钱的事了
He told you about the money.
他全都告诉我了
He told me everything.
那又怎么样
So, what is this?
是勒索还是什么
Some kind of blackmail or something?
我就是告诉你别瞧不起杰西
This is me telling you to do right by
然后把你欠他的都给他
Jesse and bring him what you owe him.
我不管这叫勒索
I don't call that blackmail.
叫作认清你自己的嘴脸
I call that you getting off your ass,
活的像个个人样
And being a decent human being.
我管这叫勒索
Well, I call it blackmail.
打我家电话  跟我老婆说话
Dialing my number. Talking to my wife.
你想怎样
And what's your end of this?
几十万块可以买多少海洛因
How much heroin does a half a million dollars buy?
我告诉你
For your information,
我是为杰西保管他的钱
I am holding Jesse's money for him,
他一分钱都不会少的
he will receive every last dollar of it.
是给他  不是你  要等到时机成熟的时候
He will... not you... at a time when I see fit.
我绝不会让他变本加厉的吸毒的
But I will not contribute to his overdose.
你跟他讲  要是他戒了毒
Now, you tell him, if he gets clean...
-是你俩都戒了毒  -告诉你
- If you both get clean... - You know what?
我收回刚刚说的  这就是勒索
I take that back. This is blackmail.
以我对你的了解
Because what I know about you...
高中教师堕落成毒贩
High school teacher turned drug dealer
妹夫的居然就还在缉毒局
With a brother-in-law in the DEA...
这可真有戏剧性啊
That'd make one hell of a story.
我打赌  会成为全国新闻
National news, I'll bet.
今晚就跟杰西两清
Do right by Jesse tonight
要不然我灭了你
Or I will burn you to the ground.
妈的
Shit.
他就是个高中老师
He's a high school teacher.
他能怎么样  给你个B减
What's he gonna do? Give you a B-minus?
把你留下来洗黑板擦
Send you outside to clap the erasers?
你不会真的去警察那里吧
You wouldn't really go to the cops, would you?
不用  他会给钱的
We won't have to. He'll pay.
要是他不给呢
What if he doesn't?
杰西  这是你该得的钱
Jesse, it's your money.
你是清白的  他才是十恶不赦呢
You're in the right here. He's in the wrong.
他不笨  会给钱的
He's not stupid. He'll pay.
怎么回事
What is it, really?
你不想要这么一大笔钱了吗
You don't want your half a million dollars?
你打算看破红尘削发为僧吗
You wanna renounce your earthly possessions and become a monk?
只是  我不是那种趁火打劫的人
It's just, I'm not the kind of dude who rolls.
再说  你也不是这样的人
And by extension, neither are you.
我是说  他是我搭档
I mean, he's my partner.
我才是你搭档
I'm your partner.
闭上眼睛  睡吧
Close your eyes and go to sleep.
要是嘲鸟不歌唱
If that mockingbird won't sing
妈妈就给你买钻石指环
Mama's gonna buy you a diamond ring
要是钻石指环变成铜
If that diamond ring turns brass.
妈妈就给你买小镜子
Mama's gonna buy you a looking glass
安静安静  宝宝别哭泣
So hush, little baby Don't you cry
爸爸和我都爱你
Daddy loves you and so do I
她终于睡着了
She's finally asleep.
你在干什么  研究大象吗
What are you doing?  Learning about elephants?
亲爱的  尿布用完了  你能出去买一下吗
Honey, we're out of diapers. Would you mind going out?
给杰西的
Jesse.
不是给你的
Not you.
你翅膀硬了啊
Nice job wearing the pants.
我怎么知道她会缄口不言
How do I know she'll keep quiet?
你不必担心
I guess you don't.
你不会再收到到我们的任何消息了
You'll never hear from either of us again.
你没看到真相  杰西
You're not seeing straight, Jesse.
你在犯错误
You are making a mistake.
-你知道这是什么吗  -一大堆干酪
- Do you know what this is?  - It's a whole lot of cheddar.
这是自由
This is freedom.
这就是说  我们可以想去哪去哪
This is saying, "I can go anywhere I want.
我无所不能
"I can be anybody."
你想成为怎样的人
What do you want to be?
你想去哪  南美  欧洲  澳洲
Where do you want to go?  South America? Europe? Australia?
新西兰是澳洲的吗
Is New Zealand part of Australia?
新西兰就是新西兰
New Zealand is New Zealand.
对啊
Right on.
新西兰  就是"指环王"的拍摄地
New Zealand. That's where they made "Lord of the Rings"
我们干脆搬到那里去  你搞你的艺术创作
I say we just move there, yo. I mean, you can do your art.
行吗  你可以画当地的城堡之类的
Right?  Like, you can paint the local castles and shit
我可以做探险飞行员
And I can be a bush pilot.
新西兰  可以啊
New Zealand. I can get behind that.
我觉得只要我俩在一起  去哪里都好
But I guess I'm good anywhere as long as it's the two of us.
我们得先戒毒
But first we gotta get clean.
并不是因为有谁逼我们这么做
And not because anybody's telling us to.
是为咱俩好  懂吗
We do this for us, right?
当然了
Absolutely.
-为咱俩  -所有这些
- For us. - All this here...
我们再也不往胳膊里打这些东西了
We're not gonna just shoot this up our arms.
绝不
We're not.
不
Hell, no.
我们是好人
We're better than that.
我们是大好人了  现在
We're way better than that. I say...
我们把剩下的冲走  然后今晚就出发
I say we flush what we've got left and we start tonight.
可以
We can do that.
当然了
Definitely.
抱歉
Excuse me.
需要什么吗
What can I get you?
给我一杯比利时黑啤[新比利时酒厂著名产品]
Give me a Fat Tire draft, please.
该死
Damn it.
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
真不知道该怎么跟你说
No. I don't know what to tell you.
我去了三家商店
Three stores I've been to so far,
每家都没货
And not one of them have it in stock.
尿布又不是必备商品
Do they have to be diapers for newborns?
我们看能否加大个尺码  只是
What if we went up a size and just kind of...
行  行  我懂了
All right. No, I understand.
行  我再去找找
All right. I'll just... I'll just keep looking.
我正在往沃尔玛去
I'm pulling into Wal-Mart now, so...
演得真好
Well played.
他们在火星上发现了水
They found water on Mars.
确实是这样
They have indeed.
但是却不知道如何利用这个信息
Don't exactly know what to do with that information,
但是上帝保佑  他们发现了
but God bless them, they found it.
实际上  他们
Actually, they
理论上可以从氧气中分离出氢气
Theoretically can separate the hydrogen from the oxygen
然后用于飞船的燃料
And process that into providing fuel for man's space flights.
从表面上将火星变成加油站
Ostensibly turning Mars into a giant gas station.
那么
So, it's a...
我们生活在一个新奇的时代
We live in an amazing time.
为火星上的水干杯
To water on Mars.
你的孩子怎么样
So, what'd you have?
女孩还是男孩
Girl or boy?
是个女孩
A little girl.
不错啊
That's nice.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
我有个女儿
I have a daughter.
多大了
How old?
长很大了
Old enough to know better.
下个月就27岁
27 next month.
有其他孩子吗
You have other kids?
只有这一个
Just the one.
我还有个16岁的儿子
I've got a 16-year-old boy.
快16岁了
Well, he's almost 16.
现在孩子长得快啊
There's a spread.
他挺能帮忙的
But he helps out, though.
现在他都可以帮忙换尿布了
He's even changing some diapers now, so...
比我那时要能干多了
It's more than I managed to do when I was his age.
孩子们如今成长起来可快了  我觉得
Kids today grow up faster, I think.
可能是吧
Maybe so.
那么有没有什么建议呢
So, any advice?
养女儿这方面的
Having a daughter.
有什么建议
Any advice?
没什么特别的
Not really.
就要爱他们
Just love them.
我是说  他们
I mean, they...
他们拥有属于自己的权利
They are who they are.
我有个  外甥
I've got this... nephew.
这个外甥  我是说  他是成年人了
This nephew who is... I mean, he's an adult.
但是你还是不能放任他们
But you can't infantilize them,
你也不能掌控他们的生活
you can't live their life for them.
但仍会有不愉快的事
But still, I mean, there is that frustration.
天  从小到大总有这种不愉快的事
God, that frustration that goes along with,
"是的  事实就是  我很了解
"Yes, as a matter of fact, I do know
你该做什么  所以你听好"
What is best for you, so listen."
但是当然了  他们可不这么想
But of course, they don't.
你遇到这种情况怎么处理呢
What do you do with someone like that?
家人
Family.
你绝对不能抛弃你的家人  绝对不能
You can't give up on them. Never.
除此之外  你就身无他物了
I mean, what else is there?
是我
It's me!
我只是想谈谈
I just want to talk.
醒醒
Wake up.
快醒醒